# SHIVAM VERMA

Email: sverma39@asu.edu

Phone no: +1 480 (868)-4002 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivam-verma-125b5a110/ GitHub: https://github.com/ShivamVerma920302/

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Developer, skilled in Python, Java, and SQL with an experience of 2+ years in the field of information technology with a comprehensive background in web application development with an extensive knowledge in the field of programming, data analysis, visualization, business intelligence, database management and Azure Cloud Services. Currently Seeking Internship Opportunities in Software Development/Data Engineering from Summer 2019.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Software Engineering at Arizona State University

Fall 2018 - Spring 2020

July 2011 - May 2015

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering at JIIT.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages - Java, SQL, Python, C#, HTML5/HTML, JavaScript

Tools and Technology – Django, AWS, Azure, Power BI, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Git, PowerShell, Agile, Scrum, Spark, Hadoop, NoSQL, MS SQL Server, Tableau, Linux, Travis CI, Docker, Rest API

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2, MAQ Software

Mar 2016 - July 2018

#### Develop solution to assist business and finance

- Centralized ETL for more than 26 upstream sources by creating an automated data refresh application through SSIS.
- Processed data collected at data staging layer by writing stored procedure and storing data as facts and dimensions in Data warehouses.
- Created OLAP Cube (SSAS) to assist clients in Sales Trend Analysis through Metrics as WoW, MoM, YoY etc.
- Established a release management using GIT and RM for automated backend deployments with adherence to all SDLC principles.

#### Analysis of Microsoft Partner's Journey

- Analyzed data points of Partner's Journey in SQL and Python and created Power BI Dashboard to report KPI throughout the journey of partner.
- Tracked conversion rate of partner and provided solution to increase retention rate at each Key Touch Points.
- Created a machine learning model to classify and notify Microsoft when its partner is at risk.

### Revamped the old architecture using the modern cloud-based technology i.e. Microsoft Azure.

- Created scalable, resilient data pipelines in the cloud using Azure Data Factory.
- Processed petabytes of data in Azure Data Lake coming from different sources to store it as Facts and Dimension on Azure SQL Datawarehouse.
- Created Tabular Model using Azure Analysis Services and reported the data in Power BI Dashboard.

#### Created a C# utility to Load Test a Power BI Report

- Created an automated C# utility to perform Load Testing of Power BI report using Visual Studio Load Test APIs.
- Logged CPU usage and Memory Utilization of Server using PowerShell scripts and created KPI to benchmark performance.

# Created and analyzed huge sets of data collected from Microsoft Store using Microsoft's big data platform.

- Embedded complex business logic in Scope language and high-level language C# to pull the relevant data.
- Analyzed the data after dumping the data into a database or excel to make business decisions.

# Business Intelligence Developer, University Technology Office at Arizona State University

Oct 2018 - Present

- Created scripts in python/node.js for meta data collection and used AWS lambda to invoke functions via handler objects.
- Enhanced existing scripts by adding event logging and handling errors.

# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

# Movie Showtime Finder (http://showtimefinder.azurewebsites.net)

September 2018 - Present

Developed an Intelligent Movie web app implementing MVT architecture using Django/Python to displays the movie showtime and recommend
movie based on user's interest. Recommendation engine is built using collaborative filtering and deep neural networks.

#### Real Time Analysis of Twitter Data using Spark MLlib and Spark Streaming.

Analyzed twitter data in real-time using Apache Spark Ecosystem (Spark Streaming and Spark MLlib) to receive feedback after a product launch.

### Sentiment Analysis of Customer Feedback

Implemented Sentiment Analysis of Customer Feedback using NLTK in Python.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certificate in Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014 (70-461), Developing SQL Databases (70-762), Performing Cloud Data Science with Azure Machine Learning (70-774), Analyzing and Visualizing Data in Power BI (70-778)
- Certificate in Certificate in Data Warehousing for Business Intelligence, a 5-course specialization by University of Colorado (Coursera)